We made it...
Your knees okay?
I think so...
Hey, you guys!
What are you doing here?!
Alafatra Mountain Range
3800 meters above sea level
This is the front lines... the very front!
The Fate of a Small Honor
So, things are bad enough
that you're being sent here?
Um, First Lieutenant?
Actually, it's "Captain" now.
Just provisionally, though.
My apologies, Captain.
Would you tell us
the current state of the war?
Yeah.
We're nearing the end.
Three forces are heading to fight
the Sinack via separate mountain routes.
When the enemy splits up,
we whittle them down,
then meet up on the ground at the other side.
Therefore driving the enemy
into a single, decisive battle.
That's Lieutenant General Safida's plan, huh?
Um, Captain Sazaluf,
may I ask a few things?
No pointing out fundamental
problems with the plan.
Too late for that now.
You've made it this far.
We've got lots of safe jobs for you to do.
I know. I'll combine all five of
your platoons into one company.
Warrant Officer Ikta, from now
on you're company commander.
Congratulations.
Right, got it.
So what, exactly, should we do?
First, the simple job of
starting the bonfires.
Don't let their whining get to you.
As if killing us and
stealing from us wasn't enough,
now you burn our homes?
You are monsters!
Ah, please wait a little longer.
As soon as the flames go out,
we'll take you to a village to the west.
Looks like I underestimated Captain Sazaluf.
Especially his sense of humor,
if he's calling arson "lighting bonfires."
This was better than it
could have been, though.
What if we'd been ordered to kill them?
That would've been the plan
if the Captain hadn't spoken up.
He's burning their villages and
isolating the people in another area.
He's cutting off the enemy's supply source,
and he can use them for negotiations.
It's a hell of a lot better than Lieutenant
General Safida's haphazard strategy.
I was shocked when I saw that map.
All the routes we're following are
separated by over 100 kilometers.
The forces can't help one another,
and it's clear we're going to see
a lot of deserters.
It's a massive failure as a strategy.
And to make matters worse, not only are
we paying the price for these mistakes,
but so are the Sinack.
Unlike this area, where the Captain's
plan was put into effect,
everyone is being slaughtered
in the villages to our rear.
Nothing about this is scientific.
It's a ridiculous war.
Sinack Village Refugee Camp
Okay, eight to this house.
We can have the Sotoi family here,
and then...
Ow!
Get lost, imperial dog!
Next, the Gitonko family can go...
Give it back!
Give back our village!
Young man, I understand.
Once this is done, I promise
we'll disappear completely.
Can you let me go?
What are you doing, you wretch?!
Brave boy!
Are you all right?
I apologize for my comrade's behavior!
That nosebleed is a sign that you
stood up against something unfair!
It's something to be proud of!
Splendid!
I punished the man who did this to you.
But that is probably not enough.
Now we match, young hero.
A-Are you okay?
How dare you lay hands on a child?
I'm disgusted with you, Ikta Solork.
How could you do that?
We have our reasons—
You have a problem with it?
No, I don't.
Thank you.
While you're at it,
think you could take care
of getting them set up?
I don't think they'll hate you.
Of course, gladly, but...
Thanks.
Why did you back down?!
Making a child bleed was my mistake.
Warrant Officer Deinkun handled it for me.
I should be grateful.
I refuse to accept that!
We're at war!
Our job is...
to kill lots of them.
He should be doing the same thing!
It's hypocrisy!
Hey, Suya, if you think
unconditional kindness is good,
and any sort of kindness that comes
with conditions is hypocrisy,
you should reconsider.
People can only achieve
as much as the situation allows.
But...
We have to kill the ones who fight us,
but I want to take care of the ones
who aren't fighting us as best I can.
Warrant Officer Deinkun's just like us.
It hurts him to fight our comrades.
The same?!
You had rocks thrown at you
and got punched so hard,
your face is swollen!
Sorry, Suya.
I just choose the right one for the job.
Warrant Officer Deinkun's
a real knight, not like me.
He shouldn't be doing the jobs
that make people hate him, right?
Several Days Later
Camp, 4200 meters above sea level
The end of the battle draws near!
The remaining Sinack forces
are gathering in a large village
on the other side of this canyon!
That will probably be the
location of the last battle!
I ask you to fight hard
and make their blood an offering to those
who have fallen here on Great Alafatra!
We leave in the morning,
so for tonight, rest up for the last battle!
Dismissed!
The average age here looks a lot
younger than when we started.
Of course it does.
We started with 18,000 men in three brigades.
Now we've got less than half of that.
And most died from altitude sickness,
not wounds.
Completely ridiculous.
Haro, want to go wipe ourselves down?
We can use hot water tonight, it seems.
That sounds great.
I'll go with you.
Hey, I wanted to ask you something...
What is it, Ma-kun?
How do you handle them during the war?
I mean...
your... needs.
Matthew, my friend.
That question divides us
into two types of people.
Heroes who rely on bonds with others,
or warriors who live in solitude.
That's quite the metaphor.
Torway, which are you?
A hero or a warrior?
I-I don't really...
Cut him some slack, Matthew.
Hotties like him are usually
stubborn warriors.
Yeah, maybe.
But the question here is about you, Ikta.
Intercourse during wartime,
both hetero- and homosexual,
is against military regulations.
Why are you, of all people,
bringing up regulations?!
From what you just said, I bet
you're doing it with somebody.
Who is it?
Someone from your platoon?
Come on, even I know better than that—
Another platoon, then?
No, maybe it's more realistic
to assume it's another officer.
Could it be Yatori or Haro?!
Matthew, can you imagine an Igsem
family heir breaking military regulations?
And Haro's a lot more proper than she looks.
Good to see you've got lots of energy,
but if you're gonna talk
about that, keep it down.
I-I'm sorry!
This is embarrassing, Ma-kun.
So sorry.
By the way, how are you
handling it, Captain Sazaluf?
A former hero, I guess.
Not that I can talk about it.
As I'd expect from an elder.
When we get back to base,
tell me the stories of your glory.
Some day.
Jeez, that sucked.
Let's go back.
So, my friend Matthew, what about you?
It's not fair to just run away, is it?
Now, tell me.
Are you a hero?
Or a warrior?
P-Pay your respects to a lonely warrior!
Sir, yes, sir!
I don't like this terrain.
Um, are you worried about air mortars
being fired from the other side?
If they were to just line up and
start firing, we'd be helpless.
That's a legitimate concern,
but I don't think it's likely.
Why?
It wouldn't be easy to get mortars up there.
And if they had,
we would be able to see it from here.
But there's no sign of them, huh?
I see.
No, Captain Sazaluf. Better safe than sorry.
Why don't we put shields on the side
of the officer candidates unit?
What he just said actually convinced me.
I feel the same,
but it may not be cannonballs we're facing.
Captain, I take back my earlier words.
Would you give the order to
protect our flank with shields?
Are you serious?
That means we'd have to get off our horses.
So would Lieutenant
General Safida over there.
Of course.
And the highest-ranking officer
who can make that proposal is...
What?
You want me off my horse?
Um, I know this will be an additional
strain on you, Lieutenant General.
I'm very sorry, but...
We should prepare for an attack.
Too much caution is no
different than cowardice.
I'm so lame.
Captain Senpa Sazaluf?
May I say one thing?
Oh, god... now what?
You are the best superior
officer we could have.
I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
Don't tease your elders, guys.
That was the flash signal.
The attack is beginning.
Our only target is Tamtooktsk Safida,
Commander of the Northern Garrison.
We'll go under the cover of the Sinack
attack and complete our mission.
Once again, no casualties are permitted.
Be prepared to dive into the canyon,
but only if you cannot avoid it.
We cannot shame ourselves by leaving corpses.
Begin the operation.
Kala Karm, heading out.
Enemy attack!
The mountains are our world!
Watch and be amazed, demons of the plains!
D-Directly above?
How did they get troops directly above us?
Calm down, Matthew.
They've been pushed to the brink
and into a desperate attack.
Right.
As long as we can stay calm...
Gunfire?
From above?
No! From the other side!
Damn it!
The other side?
Don't be stupid!
That's 200 meters away!
Air guns can't shoot that far—
Ikkun, they've got them, too?
That's right. They're using air rifles.
Torway, hurry!
Your men are the only ones with air rifles!
Roger! I'll put down suppressing fire!
I'll protect Lieutenant General Safida!
From above!
They're coming down!
Ready bayonets!
I can't get it to fit!
Haro, above!
I'm here to help!
Stand up, Ikta Solork.
Even I'm not saving you a second time.
Thanks, Warrant Officer Deinkun,
but this is the second time you've saved me.
What happened at the village doesn't count.
Sorry for damaging your honor back then.
Don't worry.
I never had honor that could be damaged by
a punch to the face and time on the ground.
What would damage it, then?
Being unable to say what I wanted,
when I wanted to say it,
or being unable to protect someone
when I wanted to protect them.
Probably something like that.
I don't understand that,
but I do understand one thing.
You and I are very different.
However, in the end...
You're a knight, too.
Lieutenant General Safida,
please do not move from there.
We meet again, Red One.
I feel lucky for this opportunity,
chieftain of the Sinack.
I'm Warrant Officer Yatorishino Igsem
of the Army.
My partner is the fire spirit Shia.
I am Nanaku Daru, chieftain of the Sinack.
My Hahashiku is Hisha of the Wind.
I'll give you my name,
but I won't bother remembering your rank.
That's fine.
Just remember the feeling
of my blade as you die!
Shut up!
What's wrong, Red One?
Can't even fight back?
What an unorthodox method...
Rule-breaking, but beautiful.
Stop already!
No, I won't!
A horizontal to vertical spin?
Bingo!
From the other side again?
No!
From below the cliff!
They're...
Impertinence...
I'll defeat them!
Don't rush in!
They're different from the others!
I'm amazed you withstood that.
It was taking all I've got.
But that's enough.
I've learned your techniques.
Learned my techniques?
Silence!
Regret your arrogance in the next world!
There won't be a second time!
You fell for it!
That pea shooter won't be enough...
How... did you...
How did I find out about this?
Several things didn't add up.
You didn't seem to be
carrying a spirit with you,
but you gave his name anyway.
That was all?
No.
What really made me notice
was the bold way you fought.
Every swordswoman knows better
than to leave her back exposed.
That's why I was sure.
You had something up your sleeve.
Hisha, was it?
Move and I'll kill your mistress.
The battle is over.
Tell your tribe to surrender, Nanaku Daru.
What are you...
Nana, live!
Hisha!
Warrant Officer Deinkun!
Matthew Platoon, surround them!
We let her get away, huh?
Dein! Dein!
Don't die!
Yatori, you do it.
What did he say?
"Take care of my comrades in the Empire."
And he asked me a question.
"Was I able to uphold my honor as a knight?"
What did you say?
Deinkun Hargunska fought
more bravely than anyone,
and loved the Empire and his comrades.
Glory and blessings be upon his soul.
Hisha, I'm sorry...
I'm sorry I couldn't even
pick up your Soulstone.
I'll make those demons pay.
Just wait, everyone...
Grandma, Grandpa, I'm coming home...
August, Imperial Year 906.
The madness of the war deepened
and continued to spiral out of control.
Next time: "La Saia Alderamin."
La Saia Alderamin